十戒的传说已经流传了几千年。
The legend of the ten rings has been told for thousands of years.
每一代，故事都在成长。
Every generation, the story grows.
但在它的中心总是有一个人。
But at its centre there is always one man.
有人说他是在火山口找到戒指的，或者是从坟墓里偷出来的。
Some say he found the rings in a crater or stole them from a tomb.
他们将神的能力和永生的恩赐赐给他。
They gave him the strength of a god, and the gift of eternal life.
他本可以用它们做好事的。
He could have used them for good.
但他想要的只是权力。
But all he wanted... was power.
他把他的军队叫做"十戒"
He called his army The Ten Rings.
几个世纪以来，它们传播到了世界的每一个角落。
Over the centuries, they spread into every corner of the world.
他们在阴影中移动……
They moved in the shadows...
推翻政府……
Toppled governments...
改变了历史的进程
And changed the course of history.
他追逐金钱和权力达一千年之久。
He chased money and power for a thousand years.
但他还想要更多。
But he still wanted more.
你听说过大罗的传说吗?
Have you heard the legend of Ta Lo?
一个有着神秘生物和古老魔法的隐藏村庄。
A hidden village with mythical creatures and ancient magic.
在那里人们练习一种来自神的武术风格。
Where people practise a martial arts style from the gods.
我想找到它。
I want to find it.
当然可以。我将派一名侦察员去探索这个地区，然后带着更多的信息回来。
Of course. I'll send a scout to explore the area, and come back with more information.
我想现在就走。
I want to go now.
森林在移动
The forest... ...is moving.
他在地球上已经没有什么可征服的了。
He had nothing left on Earth to conquer.
然后他就来我家了。
That's when he came for my home.
大罗的入口在哪里?
Where's the entrance to Ta Lo?
你在我们村里不受欢迎。
You're not welcome in our village.
你不知道你在跟谁说话。
You don't know who you're talking to.
我不管你是谁。
I don't care who you are.
现在转过身来，我就不用伤害你了。
Turn around now, and I won't have to hurt you.
这是所有吗?
Is that all?
那是我第一次见到你父亲。
That was the first time I met your father.
他是我最不会爱上的人。
He was the last person I thought I'd fall for.
但爱情却另有打算。
But love had other plans.
上气，关于指环的传说还有很多要知道，等你长大了你就知道了。
Shang-Chi, there's much more to know about the legend of the rings, but you'll learn about that when you're older.
如果爸爸的戒指那么强大，你是怎么打败他的?
If Dad's rings were so powerful, how did you beat him?
在我的家乡，伟大的守护者赋予了我们力量。
Where I'm from, we are empowered by the magic of the Great Protector.
当你有龙之心的时候，你就能做一些不可思议的事情。
When you have the heart of our dragon, you can do some amazing things.
你还能做那些事吗?
Can you still do those things?
我把那些超能力留给了我们的龙，但我得到的回报要好得多。
I left those powers in Ta Lo with our dragon, but what I got in return is so much better.
我想把这个给你。
I want you to have this.
每当你感到迷茫的时候，这将帮助你找到回家的路。
Whenever you feel lost, this will help you find your way home.
你还记得吗?
Can you remember that?
好吧。
Okay.
你好，先生，欢迎来到费尔蒙……我开车。
Hello, sir, welcome to the Fairmont... I'm driving.
不,你不是……凯蒂。
No, you're not... Katy.
嘿，嘿，回来。
Hey, hey, get back here.
把钥匙给我。
Give me the key.
请把门打开。
Please open the door.
哦,我的上帝。
Oh, my God.
——离开。-你上车!
- Get out. - You get in!
听着，如果这事发生了，我们下半辈子就会失业负债累累了。
Look, if happens to this thing, we're gonna be jobless and in debt for the rest of our lives.
哦,来吧。这辆车不会有事的。
Oh, come on. Nothing's gonna happen to this car.
我是亚洲版的杰夫·戈登。
I'm the Asian Jeff Gordon.
我不知道那是谁。
I don't know who that is.
纳斯卡史上职业生涯赢最多的?
Most career wins in all of NASCAR history?
请下车。
Please get out of the car.
肖恩，我们做了十年的朋友了?
Shaun, we've been friends for 10 years, okay?
你知道我不是白痴。
You know I'm not an idiot.
请进去。我会慢慢来的。
Please, get in. I'll go slow.
凯蒂,看…
Katy, watch the...
高中第一天见面我就知道凯蒂是个麻烦。
I knew Katy was trouble the first day we met in high school.
我经常被欺负，就像我们经常被欺负一样。
I was getting picked on a lot, for all the reasons we all get picked on a lot.
另外，我刚搬到美国，所以我的英语很糟糕，有一天我在去吃午饭的路上，有个身材是我两倍的家伙从大厅那头冲我大喊，“怎么了，江南Style?”
Plus, I had just moved to the US, so I was struggling with my English, and I was on my way to lunch one day when this guy who was like twice my size yells at me from down the hall,"What's up, Gangnam Style?"
于是我吼道，“我不是韩国人，白痴。”
So I yelled back, "I'm not Korean, idiot."
我转过街角，看到一个人把背包掉在地上，满脸通红……就在他要出手的时候，凯蒂不知从哪儿冒了出来，走到我们中间，开始大声唱《加州旅馆》的歌词。
And I turn the corner, and I see this guy drop his backpack, he's getting all up in his face... And right before he was about to throw the first punch, Katy comes out of nowhere,steps right between us and starts screaming the lyrics to Hotel California.
什么?
What?
这是一种迷惑的艺术，对愚蠢的人很有效。
It's the art of confusion. Works great on stupid people.
我们就是这样认识的。
And that's how we met.
然后我把他拉进了停车场…就在这时，她透露，她还偷走了那家伙的野马车的钥匙。
Then I pulled him into the parking lot... At which point she revealed that she had also swiped the keys to the guy's Mustang.
是啊，我们去街区兜风了。
Yeah, we went on a little joyride around the block.
你妻子也在车里。
And your wife was in the car, too.
——这是真的。你是。——什么?
- That's true. You were. - What?
我刚才坐在后座上。
I was just in the back seat.
那是车的一部分。
That's a part of the car.
那还是车的一部分。
That's still a part of the car.
你怎么从没告诉过我这个故事?
How have you never told me this story?
你知道吗，在她成为律师之前，她很狂野。
You know, before she was a lawyer, your girl was pretty wild.
哦!发生了什么事?
Oh! What happened?
我长大。
I grew up.
那是什么意思?
What's that supposed to mean?
Yeah, what's that supposed to mean?
也许在某个时刻，你应该停止飙车，开始思考如何发挥自己的潜力。
That maybe there's a point where you're supposed to stop going on joyrides and start thinking about living up to your potential.
请告诉我你在开玩笑，苏。
Please tell me you're kidding, Soo.
听着，我们现在生活的世界随时都可能有一半人口消失。
Look, we're now living in a world where at any moment half the population can just disappear.
生命太短暂，太脆弱。
Life's too short and too fragile.
凯蒂，你是泊车司机，有伯克利的荣誉学位，肖恩会说四种语言。
Katy, you're a valet driver with an honours degree from Berkeley, and Shaun can speak, like, four languages.
你们一直是我认识的最有才华的人。
You've always been the most talented people I know.
我只是不明白你为什么害怕用它来做正经事。
I just don't get why you're scared to actually use it for something serious.
哇。
Wow.
你说话像我妈妈。你穿得也有点像她。
You sound like my mom. You also... dress like her a little bit, too.
这是从哪里来的，塔尔博特?
Where's this from, Talbots?
我们不是在逃避成年。
We're not running from adulthood.
拥有自己喜欢的工作感觉如何?
How is it running to have jobs that you actually like?
是啊，这根本说不通啊。
Yeah, that doesn't even make any sense.
你觉得代客泊车很容易吗?
Did you think valet parking is easy?
这是最具挑战性的工作。
It's like the most challenging job ever.
你需要人际交往能力，驾驶技能……苏甚至不能平行停车。
You need people skills, driving skills... Soo can't even parallel park.
好了，快午夜了。我们要上早班。
Well, it's almost midnight. We got the early shift.
应该负责任，去睡吧。
Should probably be responsible, go to sleep.
是的，我们可以负责任。我们可以做到。
Yeah, we can be responsible. We can do that.
或者... 侧着身子躺在…带我的马去老城的路我要闭上眼睛我不想…
Or... Over, sideways and under on a... Take my horse to the old town road I'm gonna Close my eyes I don't wanna...
早上好,陈太太。
Morning, Mrs Chen.
她还没准备好。
She's not ready yet.
你等的时候来喝点咖啡。
Come have some joe while you wait.
凯蒂,肖恩在这里。
Katy, Shaun's here.
好的，妈妈，马上就来。
Yeah, Mom, be there in a minute.
瑞华，你应该帮你爸进货的。
Ruihua, you're supposed to be helping your dad stock the shop.
妈妈，我饿着肚子没法工作，我的腿会抽筋。
Mom, I can't work on an empty stomach, my legs get crampy.
也许肖恩可以帮他而不是每天来吃我们的食物。
Maybe Shaun can help him instead of just showing up every day to eat our food.
我很乐意帮忙。
I'm happy to help.
不，这是瑞华的工作，让他去吧。
No, it's Ruihua's job, let him do it.
原。
Waipo.
那个座位是给外公的。
That seat's for Waigong.
哦,对不起。
Oh, sorry.
今年的亡灵节他会得到他最喜欢的东西。
He's getting all his favourite things this year for the Day of the Dead.
你确定外公可以把洋葱和香烟带回来世吗?
Are you sure that Waigong's allowed to take Funyuns and cigarettes back to the afterlife?
他什么都能吃。
He can take anything.
去年我在他墓前放了一瓶威士忌...第二天早上就没了。
Last year I put a bottle of whisky on his grave... And it was gone the next morning.
我知道你们觉得这很傻。
I know you kids think it's silly.
我们不认为这很傻，Waipo。
We don't think it's silly, Waipo.
我们只知道外公希望你向前看，享受生活。
We just know Waigong would've wanted you to move on and enjoy your life.
“继续前进”是美国人的想法。
"Moving on" is an American idea.
你是美国人,妈妈!不要忘记。
You're American, Mom! Don't forget.
肖恩，我女儿这周有没有申请新工作?
Shaun, did my daughter apply to any new jobs this week?
她真的很喜欢她的工作。
She really likes her job.
我们都做。
We both do.
嗯哼。
Mm-hmm.
外公从湖南搬到这里不是为了让你靠停车谋生。
Waigong didn't move here from Hunan so you could park cars for a living.
说到这，我想我们要赶不上公车了。
Well, on that note, I think we're gonna miss our bus.
很抱歉我不能胜任这份工作。
I'm sorry for my unacceptable job.
还有昨晚在外面待到很晚，想要享受生活。
And for staying out late last night, trying to enjoy my life.
但总有一天，我会让你骄傲的，我保证。
But one day, I'll make you proud, I promise.
我为你感到骄傲，姐姐。
I'm proud of you, sis.
停车超级难。
Parking cars is super hard.
谢谢,兄弟。
Thanks, bro.
也许有一天你会通过驾照考试，像我一样实现梦想。
Maybe one day you'll pass your driver's test, live the dream like me.
来吧，肖恩，我们走。
Come on, Shaun, let's go.
你们俩什么时候结婚?
When are you two going to get married?
怀波，我们只是朋友。
Waipo, we're just friends.
好吧。走,走,走。
All right. Go, go, go.
看。看看这个。看那个女孩。
Look. Look at that. Look at that girl.
她在公车上写研究论文。
She's writing a research paper on a bus.
所以呢?
So?
这就是我妈妈希望从她阴道里生出来的女儿。
That is exactly the daughter my mom wishes came out of her vagina.
我为她感到难过。
I'm sorry about her.
它会怎么样?
How's it goin'?
把吊坠给我，就不会有人受伤。
Give me the pendant, and no one gets hurt.
你认识这个人吗?
Do you know this guy?
我不知道你在说什么，伙计。
I don't know what you're talking about, dude.
——嘿!放开我!——哇。
- Hey! Get off of me! - Whoa.
你怎么了，混蛋?
What is wrong with you, asshole?
我不想惹麻烦。
I don't want any trouble.
那就把吊坠给我们!
Then give us the pendant!
你抓错人了!
You have the wrong guy!
他看起来会打架吗?
Does he look like he can fight?
来吧,兄弟!
Come on, bro!
你没事吧?
You okay?
嘿，你们好吗?是你的伙计克莱夫，在公车上袭击了你。
Yo, what up, y'all? It's your boy Klev, comin' at you live on the bus.
我年轻的时候确实学过一点武术，所以我要试着给这场比赛打分。
I actually did take a little bit of martial arts as a youth, so I'm gonna try and grade this fight as we're goin'.
天呐
Holy shit.
你是谁?
Who are you?
你能行的，兄弟!
You got this, bro!
我的错
My bad.
不,不,不!
No, no, no!
对不起。
Sorry.
到底怎么回事?
What the hell's going on?
你真想现在谈这个吗?
You really wanna talk about this now?
巴士司机倒下了。
Bus driver is down.
我不会处理的。
I'm not gonna handle this.
每次我试着开公共汽车，都会被吼。
Every time I've tried to drive a bus, I get yelled at.
去,你狂!
Go, you freak!
请把门打开!
Open the door, please!
后面马上要走了。
The back is about to go.
听我的信号，右转。
On my signal, make a hard right.
什么信号?
What signal?
大家都到前面去!
Everybody to the front now!
走吧!走,走,走。
Go! Go, go, go.
怎么了,你们呢?怎么了,你们呢?怎么了,你们呢?
What's up, y'all? What's up, y'all? What's up, y'all?
你和你妹妹罪有应得。
You and your sister deserve what's coming.
等等,大家!
Hold on, everybody!
哦,上帝。
Oh, God.
哦,我的上帝!
Oh, my God!
对不起。哈。
Sorry. Heh.
我们合作得很好。
We make a good team.
肖恩。嘿。
Shaun. Hey.
你得告诉我到底发生了什么。
You need to tell me what the hell's going on.
你在干什么?你要去哪里?
What are you doing? Where are you going?
——澳门。——澳门?
- Macau. - Macau?
那些人接下来要找我妹妹，我得先找到她。
Those guys are going after my sister next, and I have to get to her first.
你有个妹妹?
You have a sister?
我知道这很让人困惑
Look, I know this is confusing.
等我回来再跟你解释，我保证。
I'll explain it when I get back, I promise.
不,不。
No, no.
地狱不,老兄。
Hell no, dude.
这是废话!
This is bullshit!
我陪了你半辈子。
I have been by your side for half your life.
我知道有些事你不想谈，我也不想逼你。
I get there are things you never wanted to talk about, and I never wanted to push.
但是一个拿着大砍刀的家伙把我们的车砍成了两半，肖恩!
But a guy with a freaking machete for an arm just chopped our bus in half, Shaun!
你到底是谁?
Who the hell are you?
我姐姐几个月前给我寄了这个。
My sister sent me this a few months ago.
我想这是她住的地址。
I think it's the address of where she's staying.
那些人是我爸爸派来的。
Those guys back there were sent by my dad.
什么?
What?
如果他们伤害她…
If they hurt her...
抱歉，我得走了。
I'm sorry, but I have to go.
很好。
Fine.
你可以在飞机上解释。
You can explain on the plane.
什么?不，凯蒂，你不能…你可以在飞机上解释，肖恩!
What? No, Katy, you can't just... You can explain on the plane, Shaun!
我妈妈死后…我爸爸开始训练我。
After my mom died... my dad started my training.
从早到晚，我学会了各种杀人的方法。
From sunup to sundown, I was taught every possible way to kill a man.
在我14岁的时候，我几乎不记得她死前的生活是什么样子的。
By the time I was 14, I could barely remember what life was like before she died.
这是我第一次被派去执行任务时的年龄。
That's how old I was when he sent me on my first assignment.
我愿意为他做任何事。
I was willing to do anything he wanted.
如果他让我烧了这个世界，我会问他…牛肉或素食者?
If he asked me to burn the world down, I would've asked him... Beef or vegetarian?
鸡肉都卖完了，所以我只能给你牛肉或素食?
We're all out of the chicken, so I can only offer you beef or vegetarian?
嗯…-素食很好。——是的,一样的。
Um... - Vegetarian would be great. - Yeah, same.
——好的。——谢谢。
- Okay. - Thank you.
所以…我们也没有素食了。
So... Oh, we're out of the vegetarian too.
现在我们只有牛肉了。
Now we only have beef.
牛肉。因为那是你的全部，对吧?
Beef. 'Cause that's all you have, right?
-好吧，你吃牛肉。——是的。
- Okay, you'll have the beef. - Yes.
- - -…——牛肉。
- And... - Beef.
-还有牛肉。——两个争吵。
- And the beef. - Two beefs.
你做了吗?
Did you go through with it?
我知道我不能回到他身边，所以我就跑了。
I knew that I couldn't go back to him, so I just... ran.
我知道这对你来说很难接受。
I know this is a lot to dump on you.
你妈妈的事我很遗憾。
I'm sorry about your mom.
我可能还应该提一下，严格来说我的名字不叫肖恩。
I should also probably mention that my name's not technically Shaun.
什么?
What?
它是什么?
What is it?
商迟。
It's Shang-Chi.
Shaun-Chi。
Shaun-Chi.
不。商迟。
No. Shang-Chi.
Shaun-Chi。
Shaun-Chi.
商。
Shang.
——肖恩。——商。
- Shaun. - Shang.
山。
Shan.
S-H-A-N-G。商。
S-H-A-N-G. Shang.
商吗?
Shang?
是的。
Yeah.
你把名字从尚改成肖恩了?
You changed your name from Shang to Shaun?
是的,我不…是的。
Yeah, I don't... Yeah.
我想知道你父亲是怎么找到你的。
I wonder how your father found you.
好吧，那时我才15岁。好吧?
Okay, I was 15 years old. All right?
你的改名逻辑是什么?
What is your name change logic?
你要躲起来了。
You're going into hiding.
——好的。-你的名字是Michael，把它改成Mishael。
- Okay. - And your name is Michael, you go on and change it to Mishael.
事实并非如此。
That's not what happened.
就像，“嗨，我叫吉娜。
It's like, "Hi, my name's Gina.
“我要躲起来了。我的新名字是吉娜。”
"I'm gonna go into hiding. My new name's Gina."
听不到你说的话了。我很抱歉。
Can't hear you. I'm sorry.
是的,好的。哦，是的，你能听到我说话。
Yeah, okay. Oh, yeah, you can hear me.
请在这里签名。
Sign here to get in.
我在找我的妹妹，徐霞玲。
I'm looking for my sister, Xu Xialing.
你听说过她吗?
Have you heard of her?
这是她给我的地址。
This is the address she gave me.
好吧。
Okay.
看起来是个不错的人。
Seems like a nice fella.
这电梯绝对符合标准。
And this elevator is definitely up to code.
绝对不可能从大楼上掉下来……
There's absolutely no chance of it just falling off the side of the building...
巴士男孩!
Bus Boy!
嗯…三天浏览量200万，老兄!
Uh... Two million views in three days, bro!
该死的,伙计。
Damn, dude.
哦,不。
Oh, no.
而你是司机!
And you're the driver!
哦，我的中文糟透了。
Oh, my Chinese sucks.
哦,都很好。
Oh, all good.
-我会说A-B-C。——哦,太棒了。
- I speak A-B-C. - Oh, great.
-我是乔恩·乔恩。——乔恩·乔恩。
- I'm Jon Jon. - Jon Jon.
欢迎来到金匕首俱乐部。
Welcome to the Golden Daggers Club.
好了，让我们为战斗做好准备。
Okay, let's get you ready to fight.
等。什么?
Wait. What?
我们是一个多平台的全球公司。
We're a multi-platform global operation.
每一场战斗都在暗网上直播。
Every fight livestreamed on the dark web.
我们说话的同时，成千上万的观众在下注。
Thousands of viewers placing bets as we speak.
这会把你的品牌提升到一个全新的高度。
This is gonna take your brand to a whole new level.
我想一定是搞错了。
Think there's been some sort of confusion.
我喜欢你的尖头脸。
I like your spike face.
谢谢!
Thanks!
通常情况下，要想登上拳坛的中心，你得努力争取，但像你这样的明星?
Usually, you gotta fight your way to centre ring, but a viral star like you?
排在前面，宝贝。
Front of line, baby.
我不是来和任何人打架的。好吧?
I'm not here to fight anybody. Okay?
我在找我的妹妹，徐霞玲。
I'm looking for my sister, Xu Xialing.
从没听说过她。
Never heard of her.
我们在最后一分钟失去了一名拳手，所以下一个位置是你。
We just lost a fighter at the last minute, so you get the next slot.
好,海伦。
Nice one, Helen.
他会穿着这个打架吗?
Is he gonna be fighting in one of these?
哦，不，不，不。这些都是低级别的打斗。
Oh, no, no, no. These are like low-level fights.
你要在上面战斗。
You're gonna be fighting up there.
真伤人,埃米尔
That hurt, Emil.
你想让我告诉你这是什么感觉吗?
You want me to show you how it feels?
黄!黄!黄!
Wong! Wong! Wong!
走,黄!
Go, Wong!
我总是赌亚洲人赢。
I always bet on Asian.
哦,我的上帝。
Oh, my God.
听着，我不会上去的，好吗?
Yeah, look, I'm not going up there, okay?
-我只是想…-哇，哇，哇。
- I'm just trying to... - Whoa, whoa, whoa.
现在打退堂鼓已经太晚了。
It's too late to back out now.
-你已经承诺过了，兄弟。——什么?
- You already committed, bro. - What?
你签了合同，记得吗?
You signed the contract, remember?
你的名字在花名册上。
Your name's on the roster.
赌注越来越多。
The bets are piling in.
——真的吗?我们将是什么?-太大了。
- Really? What's our cut? - Oh, it's huge.
没关系。
It doesn't matter.
它很重要。
It matters.
哥们，我看到你在一辆行驶的公共汽车上和五个杀手还有一个胳膊上拿着剃刀的罗马尼亚巨人搏斗。
Dude, I saw you fight five assassins and a giant Romanian with a razor for an arm on a moving bus.
这只是一个人。
This is just one guy.
想做就做。然后我们都拿到钱，然后我会帮你找到你要找的人。
Just do it. Then we all get paid, and then I'll help you find whoever you're looking for.
来吧。你得到这个。
Come on. You got this.
-你能行的。-别紧张。
- You got this. - Don't be nervous.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
-是的。-是的。
- Yeah. - Yeah.
下巴怎么样?
How's the jaw?
也许你该开始像我们练习的那样控制出拳了?
Maybe you'll start controlling those punches like we practised?
爱那个人。
Love that guy.
现在把你的衬衫脱了。
Now take your shirt off.
女士们先生们，我们期待已久的比赛。
Ladies and gentlemen, the fight we've all been waiting for.
令人难以置信的病毒式轰动，来自美国旧金山的巴士男孩!
The incredible viral sensation, all the way from San Francisco, USA, it's Bus Boy!
你的衬衫怎么了?
What happened to your shirt?
而他今晚的对手，是澳门的杀手…
And his opponent for tonight, it's Macau's own fearsome killer...
徐霞玲!
Xu Xialing!
妹妹。
Sister.
等等,等等!
Wait, wait!
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
我知道你很生气。
I know you're upset.
但你能听我说完吗?
But can you hear me out?
我们没时间了。
We don't have time for this.
哦，那一定很疼。
Ooh, that's gotta hurt.
你能不能别打我了?
Can you please stop hitting me?
住手! 我是在帮你！
Stop it! I'm trying to help you!
爸爸来接你了。
Dad's coming for you.
我不是在跟你打架。
I'm not fighting you.
你不应该回来的。
You shouldn't have come back.
有时当我做表格的时候，我会闭上眼睛，就好像我能感觉到她。
Sometimes when I'm doing my forms... I close my eyes, and it's like I can feel her.
你有过这种感觉吗?
Do you ever feel like that?
不。
No.
我知道你要去那里做什么。
I know what you're going there to do.
我不知道他在跟你说什么，但是…妈妈已经死了。
I don't know what he's telling you, but Mom... Mom's dead.
请不要把我留在这里。
Please don't leave me here.
我三天后回来。
I'll be back in three days.
徐霞玲，你太棒了!
Xu Xialing, you're amazing!
我们爱你，徐霞玲!哇!
We love you, Xu Xialing! Whoo!
这地方是你管的?
You run this place?
我拥有它。
I own it.
你从哪儿弄来那么多钱?
Where'd you get all that money?
你赌我输了吗?
Did you bet against me?
不。
No.
嗨,轴流。我是凯蒂。
Hi, Xialing. I'm Katy.
你真是个坏蛋。
You're, like, such a badass.
你做的每件事都很酷。
Everything that you do is, like, so cool.
那真的很酷。
That was really cool.
我喜欢你的裤子。
I like your pants.
谢谢你！谢谢。是的。
Thank you. Thanks. Yeah.
你想要什么?
What do you want?
十戒帮在旧金山埋伏了我们。
The Ten Rings ambushed us in San Francisco.
我看了视频。
I saw the video.
他们拿走了我的吊坠。
They took my pendant.
他们下一个就会来抢你的。
They're gonna come for yours next.
我不知道他想要他们做什么，但我们都知道不会是好事。
I don't know what he wants with them, but we both know it can't be good.
你知道他离开时对我说了什么吗?
You know what he said to me when he left?
“我三天后回来。”
"I'll be back in three days."
三天后，我去了妈妈的神龛等她。
And after three days, I went to our mom's shrine and waited.
三天变成了一周，一周变成了一个月，一个月变成了六年。
Three days turned into a week, a week turned to a month, and a month turned to six years.
我花了很长时间才意识到我不再需要他了。
That's how long it took me to realise I didn't need him any more.
这地方是我自己建的。
I built this place on my own.
我那时不需要你，现在也不需要你。
I didn't need you then, and I don't need you now.
那你为什么要寄明信片给我?
Then why would you send me the postcard?
什么明信片?
What postcard?
我没把这个发给你。
I didn't send you this.
有后门吗?
Is there a back exit?
肖恩。
Shaun.
嘿。嘿!嘿,开放!
Hey. Hey! Hey, open up!
她走了,伙计。
She's gone, dude.
我们该怎么办?
What do we do?
嗯…
Uh...
来吧!
Come on!
哦,没有地狱。去你的!我不会这么做的。
Oh, hell no. Screw you! I'm not doing this.
如果我们能坐上电梯，我们可以在下一层跳进去。
If we make it to the elevator, we can hop in on the next floor.
凯蒂，我们别无选择了。我们得走了。
Katy, we're out of options. We have to go now.
一,二,三
One, two, three.
哇。
Whoa.
直接去那部电梯。
Just head straight for that elevator.
你可以的
You got this.
我会为你争取一些时间。只是继续。
I'll buy you some time. Just keep going.
在黑暗的沙漠公路上，凉风吹过我的头发
On a dark desert highway Cool wind in my hair
肖恩!
Shaun!
肖恩!肖恩!
Shaun! Shaun!
哦,我的上帝!哦!
Oh, my God! Ohhh!
我来了!
I'm coming!
肖恩!
Shaun!
坚持下去。
Hang on.
明白了。
Gotcha.
肖恩!
Shaun!
凯蒂!
Katy!
你丢下我们等死!
You left us for dead!
现在你知道这是什么感觉了。
Now you know how it feels.
他要这个吊坠干什么…
What does he want with the pendant...
美国让你变得软弱了吗?
Did America make you soft?
他拿着吊坠!
He has the pendant!
我告诉我的人，就算他们想杀你，也杀不了你。
I told my men they wouldn't be able to kill you if they tried.
很高兴我是对的。
Glad I was right.
我想念你，我的儿子。
I've missed you, my son.
我们回家吧。
Let's go home.
我儿子在家。
My son is home.
带姑娘们去她们的房间。
Take the girls to their room.
这周我看到了一些非常可怕的东西，但你爸爸的感觉，像是，一个全新的水平。
I've seen some really scary stuff this week, but your dad's on, like, a whole 'nother level.
他会杀了我们吗?
Is he gonna kill us?
只是点头。不要说话。他会忘记你在那里。
Just nod. Don't talk. He'll forget you're there.
我就是这样活下来的。
That's how I survived.
他总是那样对你吗?
He always treat you like that?
在我妈妈去世之后。
Only after my mom died.
他说他不敢看我，因为我让他想起了她。
He said he couldn't look at me because I reminded him of her.
他们不允许我和孩子们一起训练。
I wasn't allowed to train with the boys.
但我观察他们做的每一件事，并教会自己做得更好。
But I watched everything they did and taught myself to do it better.
你什么时候离开的?
When did you leave?
我16岁就离家出走了。
I ran away when I was 16.
当我知道我弟弟不会回来的时候。
As soon as I knew my brother wasn't coming back.
你十六岁的时候在澳门开了一个地下拳台?
You started an underground fight ring in Macau when you were 16 years old?
如果我爸不让我进入他的帝国，我就建立自己的帝国。
If my dad won't let me into his empire, I'm gonna build my own.
地狱是啊。
Hell yeah.
商迟。
Shang-Chi.
这就够了。
That's enough.
你一直在练习英语吗?
Have you been practicing your English?
是的。
Yes.
你必须加强你的思想和身体。
You have to strengthen your mind along with your body.
如果你想让它们有朝一日归你所有，你就得向我证明你有足够的力量来承受它们。
If you want them to be yours one day, you have to show me you're strong enough to carry them.
你怎么找到我的?
How did you find me?
我总是知道我的孩子在哪里。
I always know where my children are.
我给了你十年的生活，你得到了什么?
I gave you 10 years to live your life, and where did it get you?
现在是你在我身边的时候了。
Now it's time for you to take your place by my side.
那是不可能的。
That's not gonna happen.
美国女孩。
American girl.
她的名字叫凯蒂。
Her name is Katy.
你的中文名字是什么?
What is your Chinese name?
Ruiwen。
Ruiwen.
名字是神圣的，瑞文。
Names are sacred, Ruiwen.
它们不仅将我们与自己联系在一起，也将我们与之前的所有人联系在一起。
They connect us not only to ourselves, but to everyone who came before.
一个有趣的故事。
A funny story.
几年前，一个来自美国的恐怖分子需要一个恶魔来让你们的国家屈服。
Some years ago, a terrorist from America needed a boogeyman to bring your country to its knees.
所以他挪用了《十戒》
So, he appropriated The Ten Rings.
我十环。
My Ten Rings.
但因为他不知道我的真名，他发明了一个新名字。
But because he didn't know my actual name, he invented a new one.
你知道他选的名字吗?
Do you know the name he chose?
的普通话。
The Mandarin.
他给他的名头起了一道鸡肉菜的名字。
He gave his figurehead the name of a chicken dish.
它工作。
And it worked.
美国吓坏了。
America was terrified.
一个橙子。
Of an orange.
事实上，我这辈子有过很多名字。
The truth is, I've had many names throughout my life.
勇士之王，大汗，地球上最危险的人。
The Warrior King, Master Khan, the most dangerous man on Earth.
多年来，我一直以为那是我命中注定的。
For years, I thought that was all I was meant to be.
但当我遇到他们的母亲时，一切都变了。
But when I met their mother, everything changed.
她让我看到了我自己不知道的一部分。
She showed me a part of myself I didn't know was there.
就像我第一次看到这个世界。
It was like I was seeing the world for the first time.
为了我们能在一起，她放弃了一切。
She gave up everything so we could be together.
我也一样。
And so did I.
你知道谁在里面吗?
You know who's in there?
说，“你好，小妹妹!”
Say, "Hello, little sister!"
这么多年后，我终于找到了值得为之变老的东西。
After all those years, I finally found something worth growing old for.
我的真名是文武。
My real name is Wenwu.
只有她这么叫我。
She was the only one who called me that.
她死后…
And when she died...
我迷失了好多年。
I was lost for many years.
但我不再迷茫了。
But I'm not lost any more.
当你们离家出走的时候，我非常渴望和你们的母亲交流，我全身心投入到她村子的研究中。
When you children ran away, I was so desperate to connect with your mother, I threw myself back into the studies of her village.
传奇的大罗。
The legendary Ta Lo.
我没能找到通往村庄入口的秘密通道，但我找到了他们隐藏的东西。
I wasn't able to find the secret path to the village entrance, but I did find what they are hiding.
他们的山深处有一扇门。
There's a gate deep in their mountains.
你妈妈在那儿等我们。
Your mother is waiting for us there.
我知道这很多。
I know this is a lot.
要不是她亲口告诉我，我可能不会相信。
I might not have believed it if she didn't tell me herself.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
我当时就坐在这里，埋头研究……她跟我说话了。
I was sitting right here in this seat, deep in my research... and she spoke to me.
就好像她就站在这个房间里。
It was like she was standing in this room.
我能感觉到她的呼吸在我的脸颊上，她的手放在我的背上。
I could feel her breath on my cheek and her hand on my back.
她说她需要我的帮助。
She told me she needs my help.
要做什么?
To do what?
把她从她的族人手中救出来
To save her from her people.
我们相爱之后，你妈妈想让我们住在塔洛。
After we fell in love, your mother wanted us to live in Ta Lo.
她向长老们请求许可，但他们拒绝了。
She asked permission from the elders, and they refused.
他们说我不配。
They said I wasn't worthy.
她还会和我们在一起。
She would still be with us.
我们会一起住在那里。
We would all be living there together.
是大罗干的。
Ta Lo did this to us.
他们把她锁在门后惩罚她。
They locked her behind that gate to punish her.
你没有看见吗?
Don't you see?
她在给我们留下线索。
She's leaving clues for us.
她想让我们找到她，带她回家，这样我们就能再次成为一家人。
She wants us to find her and bring her home, so we can be a family again.
爸爸,妈妈不见了。
Dad, Mom's gone.
她不会在门后跟你说话，也不会给我们留下任何线索。
She's not talking to you from behind a gate, and she's not leaving any clues for us.
这些是什么?
Then what are these?
通往大罗的通道由一个移动的迷宫守卫着。
The passage to Ta Lo is guarded by a moving maze.
但有一条直接穿过森林的路，每年清明节才开放一次。
But there's a direct path through the forest that only opens once a year on Qingming Jie.
要想通过，你需要知道路线和它开放的确切时间。
To get through, you need to know the route and the exact time it opens.
现在我都知道了。
Now I know both.
三天后，我们将把我妻子从监狱里救出来，带她回家。
Three days from now, we will rescue my wife from her prison and bring her home.
这就是你来这里的原因。
This is why you're here.
帮我把她带回来。
To help me bring her back to us.
如果他们不让你开门呢?
And what happens if they don't let you open the gate?
我们要把村子烧成灰烬。
We'll burn the village to the ground.
什么?
What?
你不能就这么带着这些破玩意闯进我妈的村子。
You can't just march into our mom's village with this bullshit.
我是说，你知道这有多疯狂吗
I mean, do you have any idea how insane...
嘿!
Hey!
你要带我去哪里?
Where are you taking me?
你什么时候才能停止假装?
When will you stop pretending?
把他们关起来。
Lock them up.
没事的，亲爱的。
It's okay, my dear.
我们很快就要在一起了。
We're all going to be together soon.
我现在很困惑，因为一开始我觉得你爸爸应该去看心理医生治疗他的幻觉，但后来那只龙吐了一张神奇的水图，
So, um, pretty confused right now, because, uh, initially I thought your dad should definitely see a therapist for his delusions, but then that dragon vomited a magical water map,
现在我完全不知道什么是真的。
and now I have no idea what's real.
他说的你妈妈的村子是真的吗?
Is what he said about your mom's village true?
小时候她常给我们讲大罗的故事。
She used to tell us stories about Ta Lo when we were kids.
一个充满神奇生物的另一个维度的村庄。
A village in another dimension full of magical creatures.
我以为那只是个童话故事。
I thought it was just a fairy tale.
如果爸爸是对的呢?
What if Dad's right?
妈妈被自己的人锁在门后的事吗?
About Mom being locked behind a gate by her own people?
更疯狂的事情被证明是真的。
Crazier things have turned out to be true.
听着，我不知道这到底是怎么回事，但如果我们不能在他之前找到塔洛，他会毁掉我们家族的一切。
Look, I don't know what the hell is going on, but if we don't find a way to get to Ta Lo before him, he's gonna destroy everything that's left of our family.
这个家庭很久以前就被毁了。
This family was destroyed a long time ago.
那是什么鬼东西?
The hell was that?
哦。
Oh.
你要去听那声音吗?
You're going toward that noise?
“用你的敲门声把邓肯吵醒。
"Wake Duncan with thy knocking.
“哦，我想我可以。
"Oh, I would'st though could'st.
“我做的事最好不要……”
"My deed 'twere best not..."
哦,你好,爱。
Oh, hello, loves.
现在是哪一年?
What year is it?
你是谁?
Who are you?
特雷弗?Slattery吗?
Trevor? Slattery?
那个来自利物浦的演员?
The actor from Liverpool?
等
Wait.
你们是州长的孩子吗?
Are you the governor's kids?
我一直在为你的返校晚宴准备独白。
I've been preparing a monologue for your homecoming dinner.
哦。她要去哪里?
Oh. Where's she going?
你为什么在这下面?
Why are you down here?
不久前，有人让我扮演恐怖分子的角色。
Well, some time ago, I was offered the role of a terrorist.
我知道，肤浅，陈腐，我完全同意。
I know, facile, trite, I couldn't agree more.
但时局艰难，你懂我的意思吗?
But times were lean, you know what I mean?
不管怎样，制片人告诉我他为BBC工作。
Anyway, the producer told me he worked for the BBC.
但讽刺的是，他其实是个恐怖分子，而我根本不是在扮演什么角色，而是我现在认识到的你父亲的一个相当不讨人喜欢的形象。
But, ironic twist, it turns out he, in fact, was a terrorist, and I wasn't playing a character at all, but what I now recognise to be a rather unflattering portrait of your father.
我们都得到应有的惩罚。
We all got our just deserts.
制片人被钢铁侠炸了，我在联邦监狱服刑，这对我来说是最好的事。
The producer got blown up by Iron Man, and I served time in federal prison, which turned out to be the best thing for me.
我戒了毒，重拾了激情。
I got clean, I rediscovered my passion.
-然后我爸爸把你救出来了?——没错。
- Then my dad broke you out? - Exactly.
-杀了你。——没错。
- To kill you. - Exactly.
但就在他的人把我绑起来准备处决的时候，我开始表演我的《麦克白》。
But just as his men were tying me up for my execution, I launched into a performance of my Macbeth.
“敲门声是从哪儿来的?”用你的叩门把邓肯唤醒。我想我能……”
"Whence is that knocking? Wake Duncan "with thy knocking. I would'st though could'st..."
他们永远不会满足。
They couldn't get enough of it.
从那以后，我每周都为小伙子们表演。
I've been doing weekly gigs for the lads ever since.
所以你就像他的小丑?
So you're like his jester?
如果你愿意，我可以快速预览一下。
I can give you a quick preview if you like.
“叔叔,叔叔,叔叔……”
"Nuncle, nuncle, nuncle..."
谢谢，特雷弗。我想我们没事了。
Uh, thank you, Trevor. I think we're okay.
现在，我们真的需要找到一个方法…这到底是怎么回事?
Right now, we really just need to find a way to... What the hell?
什么……哦!
What the... Oh!
——哇!-那是什么?
- Whoa! - What is that?
什么是什么?
What's what?
——!那是什么?——!那!那!
- That! What is that? - That! That! That!
你能看到莫里斯吗?
You can see Morris?
莫里斯?
Morris?
哦,莫里斯!
Oh, Morris!
他们能看见你!你是真的!
They can see you! You're real!
我一直以为是我让他产生了幻觉。
All this time I thought I was hallucinating him.
这真是太棒了。
Oh, this is such fab news.
他的脸在哪里?
Where's his face?
他对此有点敏感。
He's a bit sensitive about that.
哦。真的吗?
Oh. Really?
莫里斯说他知道你是谁。
Morris says he knows who you are.
…它和你说话?
It talks... It talks to you?
如果他不跟我说话，我早就疯了。
If he didn't talk to me, I'd have gone mad yonks ago.
他怎么会认识我?
How would he know me?
他说他是和你妈妈一起长大的。在Ta瞧。
He says he grew up with your mum. In Ta Lo.
显然，你父亲是在魔法森林里找到他的那次探险。
Apparently, your father picked him up in some magic forest on one of his expeditions to find the entrance.
他想让你带他回家。
He wants you to take him home.
相信我，兄弟，如果我知道该怎么做，我会的。
Believe me, buddy, I would if I knew how.
据我爸爸说，那条路一年只开一次。
According to my dad, the path there only opens once a year.
哦。
Oh.
莫里斯说他可以马上带你过去。
Morris says he can guide you there right now.
你不需要等待路径打开就可以穿过迷宫。
You can get through the maze without waiting for the path to open.
但是，这是一个很大的“但是”
But, and it's a big "but,"
这是非常危险的。
it's very dangerous.
有多危险?
How dangerous?
没人能活着出来。
No one's ever made it out alive.
但莫里斯有百分之九十的信心能带领我们安全通过。
But Morris is 90% confident he can guide us through safely.
哦。
Oh.
19%。
19%.
听着，我做过比这更蠢的事。
Look, I've done dumber things with worse odds.
但即使那只鸡猪是对的... ...我们仍然被锁在你的…
But even if that chicken-pig is right... ...we're still locked in your...
唷!
Whew!
你是怎么……爸爸在整个院子下面有个隧道系统。
How did you... Dad has a tunnel system under the whole compound.
我上次就是这样逃出来的。
That's how I escaped last time.
哦。
Oh.
这能直接把我们带到车库。
This will take us straight to the garage.
哦,我的上帝。
Oh, my God.
我有点喜欢这家伙。
I kinda like this guy.
顺着斜坡走，穿过前门。
Just head up that ramp and through the front gate.
应该是直线射击。
Should be a straight shot.
我们大概还有30秒…你介意吗?
Figure we got about 30 seconds until he... Do you mind?
我在后面会生病。晕车的。
I get sick in the back. Carsick.
那可是我的车!
That's my car!
该死的。
God damn it.
等等。
Hold on.
还有别的出口吗?
Is there another exit?
车库的另一头。
The other end of the garage.
但我们需要指纹才能打开它。
But we need a fingerprint to open it.
来了!
Incoming!
妈的!
Shit!
后面发生了什么?
What's happening back there?
做我最好的。
Doing my best.
扫描手印，查看门禁。
Scan hand print for gate access.
——快点!——我在!
- Hurry up! - I'm trying!
扫描手印，查看门禁。
Scan hand print for gate access.
肖恩!
Shaun!
获得批准。
Access approved.
等我把她带回家，他们就会回来。
They will come back once I bring her home.
让人们备战。
Prepare the men for war.
是的,先生。
Yes, sir.
我第一次目睹了纯粹的艺术。
The first time I witnessed pure artistry.
1968. 人猿星球。
1968. Planet of the Apes.
我坐在电影院里妈妈的旁边，看着大师在我眼前展开。
I was sitting in the cinema next to my mum, watching mastery unfold before my very eyes.
看完电影后，我问她，“他们是怎么让那些猴子做那些事情的?”
After the film, I asked her, "How did they get those monkeys to do those things?"
她拍拍我的头说，“这不是真的，宝贝。这只是表演。”
And she patted me on the head and she said, "It's not real, pet. It's just acting."
那时我才知道。
That's when I knew.
如果他们能教会那些猴子如此出色地表演，想象一下我能给这个世界带来什么。
If they can teach those monkeys to act that brilliantly, just imagine what I could bring to the world.
所以你成为了一名演员，因为你认为猴子实际上…骑马吗?我做到了 是的。
So you became an actor because you thought the monkeys were actually... Riding horses? I did. Yes.
而实际上，他们只是表现得像在骑马。
When, in fact, they were simply acting as if they were riding horses.
说实话，我还是不明白。
I still can't get my head round it, to be honest.
干得好，伙计。
Good for you, dude.
你找到了你的激情，并去追求它，最终用它来削弱美国政府，但管它呢。
You found your passion and went for it, and eventually used it to cripple the US government, but whatever.
是的。不,是的,谢谢。
Yeah. No, yeah, thanks.
这真的很酷，但我们要在这坐多久?
Um, this is really cool and all, but how long do we have to sit here?
莫里斯说得很清楚。
Morris is very clear.
这一切都取决于时机。
The way through is all about timing.
好吧，但我们要谈多久?
Okay, but how long are we talking?
几个小时?几天?
Like, hours? Days?
朋友们，我只是一个短暂的容器承载着一种生物的无限智慧它远比我们所能真正理解的先进得多。
Friends, I am but a transitory vessel for the infinite wisdom of a creature far more advanced than we'll ever truly understand.
他在这个巨大的、未知的宇宙中所看到的，所感受到的，是我们简单的大脑所无法想象的……哦。你可以走了。
What he sees, what he feels of this vast, unknown universe is beyond anything our simple brains can... Oh. You can go.
什么?
What?
走了。你可以走了。他说:“走吧。”
Go. You can go. He says "go."
你应该加快速度。
You should speed up.
什么?为什么?
What? Why?
凯蒂，快，快，快!
Katy, go, go, go!
莫里斯说-数到三再右转——什么?
Morris says, - "Hard right on three." - What?
二……哪里?
Two... Hard right where?
现在。
Now.
然后离开了。
And left.
这一切都是为了不被人发现。
It's all about staying in the pocket.
——口袋里?-我们现在就在里面。
- What pocket? - We're in it now.
如果我们没钱怎么办?
What happens if we don't stay in the pocket?
森林在吃我们。
The forest eats us.
吃我们?这是什么意思?
Eats us? What does that mean?
他说它会吃了我们，走左边。
He says it eats us. Go left.
-小心!-呆在口袋里。
- Watch your back! - Stay in the pocket.
-有多近?- 5米。
- How close is it? - Five metres.
-呆在口袋里。-那是多少英尺?
- Stay in the pocket. - What is that in feet?
非常接近。
Really fricking close.
呆在口袋里。
Stay in the pocket.
你能别再说"待在口袋里"了吗?
Will you just stop saying, "Stay in the pocket"?
最后一个右转，然后一直走到尽头。
One last right, then straight on to the end.
你最好快点。
You might wanna hurry up.
你以为我在干什么?
What do you think I'm doing?
我们撑不过去了。
We're not gonna make it.
我要回家了，妈妈。
I'm coming home, Mummy.
莫里斯说:“大家干得好。”
Morris says, "Great job, everyone."
现在，我们要做的就是穿过那个瀑布，我们差不多到了。
Now, all we have to do is go through that waterfall, and we're pretty much there.
血腥的地狱。
Bloody hell.
我觉得那些鸟着火了。
I think those birds are on fire.
真的吗?哦。
Really? Oh.
莫里斯说这很正常。
Morris says it's normal.
他们是他的老朋友。
They're old mates of his.
那是匹奇怪的马。
That's a weird horse.
它为什么看着我?
What's it looking at me for?
大家好!
Hi there!
我是徐尚志。
I am Xu Shang-Chi.
这是我的妹妹，徐霞玲。
This is my sister, Xu Xialing.
我们是英莉的孩子。
We're Ying Li's children.
这是我的朋友凯蒂。
This is my friend, Katy.
上车回家去!
Get in your car and go home!
请。你不明白。
Please. You don't understand.
哇。
Whoa.
Guang Bo!
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
放下武器!
Put down your weapons!
Shang-Chi.
Xialing.
我是你的南阿姨。
I'm your aunty Nan.
我等了这么久才见到你。
I've waited so long to meet you.
你长得像你妈妈。
You look like your mother.
你好,我是凯蒂。
Hi, I'm Katy.
欢迎来到大罗，凯蒂。
Welcome to Ta Lo, Katy.
噢,谢谢你。
Oh, thank you.
看谁找到回家的路了!
Look who has found his way home!
我不是威胁。
I'm not a threat.
只是一个艺人。
Just an entertainer.
莫里斯可以为我担保。
Morris can vouch for me.
我们没有多少时间了。
We don't have much time.
我们的父亲来了。
Our father is coming.
我们的人民在这里生活了4000多年，为我们希望永远不会发生的事情做准备。
Our people have been here for over 4,000 years, preparing for something we hope will never happen.
我们是黑暗之门的守卫者，发誓要保护这个国家和你的国家不受恶魔的伤害。
We are the keepers of the Dark Gate, sworn to protect this realm and yours from the evil that's locked behind it.
我们的爸爸要来打开那扇门。
Our dad is coming here to open that gate.
他认为你把我们的妈妈关在那里。
He thinks you're holding our mom there.
他为什么会这么想?
Why would he think that?
她告诉他。
She told him.
他说他听到她在寻求帮助。
He says he can hear her asking for help.
他戴着戒指吗?
Is he wearing the rings?
自从她死后，他就没摘下过。
He hasn't taken them off since she died.
他们和这一切有什么关系?
What do they have to do with all this?
打罗的疆域远远超出了我们小村的范围。
The realm of Ta Lo stretches far beyond the shores of our small village.
我们的城市超越了你们宇宙中的任何城市，有着丰富的文化和历史。
We have cities that surpass any in your universe, rich with culture and history.
几千年前，我们所有的人都生活在和平与繁荣之中，直到黑暗者的袭击。
Thousands of years ago, all of our people lived in peace and prosperity, until the attack of the Dweller-in-Darkness.
他带着他的军队来了，吞噬他们路上的每一个人，每杀一次，他们就变得更强大。
He came with his army, devouring every soul in their path, and with each kill, they grew stronger.
在摧毁了我们最大的城市之后，他们也要去你们的宇宙做同样的事。
After decimating our largest cities, they were headed to your universe to do the same.
打罗的首领派了他们最强大的战士来阻止他们到达你们世界的入口。
The leaders of Ta Lo sent their strongest warriors here to stop them from reaching the portal to your world.
但我们的祖先不是他们的对手。
But our ancestors were no match for them.
直到伟大的护国公加入他们的战斗扭转了局势。
Until The Great Protector joined their fight and turned the tide.
他们一起把居民和他的军队推进黑暗之门，并把它锁在身后。
Together, they pushed the Dweller and his army into the Dark Gate and locked it behind them.
从那以后，我们的人民就守着那扇门，他们被伟大的守护者的魔法和她赐予我们的礼物所授权。
Our people have guarded that gate ever since, empowered by the magic of The Great Protector and the gift that she gave us.
龙鳞。
Dragon scales.
这是很好的盔甲。
Makes very good armour.
你父亲不是第一个来这里打开黑暗之门的人。
Your father isn't the first to come here to open the Dark Gate.
几个世纪以来，许多人都尝试过，但都失败了，他们都有一个共同点。
Many have tried and failed over the centuries, and they all had one thing in common.
他们是被另一边的声音吸引过来的。
They were lured here by the voice of something on the other side.
这个声音向他们承诺了他们最大的愿望。
A voice that promised them their greatest desires.
所以你认为食魂者在和我们的父亲谈话?
So you think soul eaters are talking to our dad?
他们知道十戒有能力让他们自由。
They know The Ten Rings have the power to break them free.
哦。
Oh.
给你。
Here you go.
哦。
Oh.
到靶场去
To the range.
什么?好吧。
What? Okay.
看来我要去送龙箭了。
Um, looks like I'm gonna go deliver some dragon arrows.
你要送龙箭吗?
Oh, you're gonna deliver some dragon arrows?
是的。让自己变得有用，你知道的。
Yeah. Make myself useful, you know.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
我们去看你妈妈吧。
Let's go see your mother.
我就是喜欢你们这么清楚地知道自己想做什么，并且花了一辈子的时间变得非常擅长。
I just love how you guys know exactly what you wanna do, and you spend your whole life getting really good at it.
我希望我能像你那样。
I wish I was more like that.
就像每次我稍微擅长某件事，我就放弃，开始做新的。
It's like every time I get moderately good at something, I just quit and start something new.
但我只知道自己的极限，我不会浪费时间去追求那些最终会让我失望的东西。
But I just know my own limits, and I'm not gonna waste my time chasing something that will ultimately be a disappointment for me.
那不是我。
That's not me.
Guang Bo.
让她射
Let her shoot.
如果你没有瞄准，你就什么也射不中
If you aim at nothing, you hit nothing.
你是她的一切。
You were everything to her.
她知道总有一天你会找到这里让我为你的到来准备点东西。
She knew that one day you would find your way here and asked me to prepare something for your arrival.
失去像她这样的人，在这个世界上很容易感到孤独。
After losing someone like her, it's easy to feel alone in this world.
但你不是。
But you're not.
你们是这个家庭的孩子，我欢迎你们回家。
You are children of this family, and I welcome you home.
你已经不在你父亲家了。
You're not in your father's house any more.
在大罗，我们平等训练。
In Ta Lo, we train as equals.
你在阴影里待得够久了，孩子。
You've been in the shadows long enough, my child.
广波，你看到了吗?
Guang Bo, you saw that?
这是紧张的!
That was tight!
我母亲是唯一能打败他的人。
My mother was the only one who could beat him.
告诉我她是怎么做的。
Show me how she did it.
不,对不起。
No, sorry.
对不起。越位,越位。
Sorry. Offside, offside.
你妈妈知道她是谁。
Your mother knew who she was.
你呢?
Do you?
你是所有前人的产物。
You are a product of all who came before you.
你的家庭遗产，无论好坏，都是你的一部分。
The legacy of your family, the good and the bad, it is all a part of who you are.
停止躲藏,侄子。
Stop hiding, nephew.
它只会延长痛苦。
It only prolongs the pain.
我们很快就会在一起了。
We'll be together soon.
先生。
Sir.
士兵们准备好了。
The men are ready.
通道将在黎明时打开。
The passage will open at dawn.
我去准备车辆。
I'll prepare the vehicles.
以你的呼吸为主。
Lead with your breath.
看看你的内心，光明与黑暗。
Look into your heart, the light and the dark.
要了解自己，你必须同时面对它们。
To know yourself, you must face them both.
你丈夫想毁了我们
Your husband tried to destroy us.
铁人帮是来还债的。
The Iron Gang is here to repay that debt.
我丈夫已不是过去的他了。
My husband is not the man he used to be.
没关系。
It doesn't matter.
你跟他的事跟我的孩子们一点关系都没有。
Your business with him has nothing to do with my children.
他们可以走，但总得有人付出代价。
They can go, but someone has to pay.
轴流。商迟。
Xialing. Shang-Chi.
进去。
Go inside.
我要去和我们的客人谈谈。
I'm going to talk to our guests.
但你没有超能力。
But you don't have your powers.
上气，你没什么好怕的。
Shang-Chi, you have nothing to fear.
妈妈。
Mama.
爸爸。
Papa.
她告诉我我可以改变。
She told me I could change.
我可以把过去抛在脑后。
That I could leave my past behind.
但她错了。
But she was wrong.
如果我不脱下来，那些人就不敢这么做了。
If I hadn't taken them off, those men wouldn't have dared to do this.
现在他们要为此付出代价。
And now they will pay for it.
你的老板在哪里?
Where's your boss?
我不知道!
I don't know!
我发誓我不知道!
I swear I don't!
好吧。
Okay.
血债必须用鲜血来偿还。
A blood debt has to be paid by blood.
你能帮我吗?
Will you help me?
我们找到了杀害你母亲的凶手。
We found the man responsible for killing your mother.
你有权利为我们俩了结这件事。
It is your right to finish this for both of us.
等你回来，我们会把十枚戒指重建成原来的样子。
And when you return, we will rebuild The Ten Rings to what it once was.
我到处找你。
Been looking everywhere for ya.
你没事吧?
You okay?
我不是你想的那种人。
I'm not who you think I am.
你已经为此道歉了。我们很好…我说的不是这个。
You already apologised for that. We're good... That's not what I'm talking about.
好吧。
Okay.
……它是什么?
What... What is it?
当我爸爸让我去找杀害我妈妈的凶手时
When my dad sent me to find the man who killed my mom...
我告诉过你我做不到。
I told you I couldn't go through with it.
我说谎了。
I lied.
我以为我可以改名字，开始新生活，假装什么都没发生过。
I thought that I could change my name, start a new life, pretend like it never happened.
但是…
But...
她会讨厌现在的我。
She would hate the person I've become.
你七岁时，你父亲训练你成为一名杀手。
Your dad trained you to be an assassin when you were seven.
他14岁就派你去杀人了。
He sent you on a hit at 14.
你知道这有多糟糕吧?
You realise how messed up that is, right?
我妈妈因为他而死。
My mom is dead because of him.
现在他要来毁掉她的家
And now he's coming to destroy her home.
血债必须用鲜血来偿还。
A blood debt has to be paid by blood.
你在说什么?
What are you saying?
我要做他训练我做的事。
I'm gonna do what he trained me to do.
我要杀了他。
I'm gonna kill him.
他在这里。
He's here.
不!
No!
你没有准备好。
You're not ready.
她留在这里
She stays here.
你是来帮助那些囚禁你母亲的人吗?
Are you here to help the people holding your own mother captive?
她不在后面。
She isn't back there.
你被一个想毁灭我们的生物骗了。
You're being lied to by a creature who wants to destroy us all.
他们是这么告诉你的吗?
Is that what they told you?
我认得我妻子的声音。
I know my wife's voice.
我和你一样想念我妹妹，但这不是纪念她的方式。
I miss my sister as much as you do, but this is not the way to honour her memory.
当你把她从你的门口赶走时，你尊重她了吗?
Did you honour her when you turned her away from your gate?
你傻瓜。我们拒绝了你。
You fool. We turned you away.
你过去的罪孽会毁了这个地方。
The sins of your past would have destroyed this place.
跟我说话小心点，年轻人。
Be careful how you speak to me, young man.
我活了你十辈子。
I've lived ten of your lifetimes.
让我过去
Let me pass.
我们不能那样做。
We cannot do that.
烧了它
Burn it down.
阻止他!
Stop him!
你打算一个人阻止我吗?
Are you planning to stop me all by yourself?
我不怕你。
I'm not afraid of you.
是的,你是。
Yes, you are.
你一生都在恐惧中度过。
You've spent your entire life afraid.
总是在跑，总是在躲。
Always running, always hiding.
他们来抓她的时候你在场，但你什么都没做。
You were there when they came for her, and you did nothing.
你站在窗边看着她死去!
You stood at a window and watched her die!
她走了，我们需要你。
She was gone and we needed you.
但你选择了那些该死的戒指而不是我们。
But you chose those damn rings over us.
你把你儿子训练成杀手。
You trained your son to be a killer.
这是你想要的吗?
Is this what you wanted?
就算你能让她复活，你凭什么认为她会想和你有任何关系?
Even if you could bring her back, what makes you think she'd want anything to do with you?
救救我。
Save me.
救救我吧，亲爱的。
Save me, my dear.
救救我。
Save me.
我来了，亲爱的。
I'm coming, my love.
他攻破了大门！
He breached the gate!
如果我们不合作，那些东西会杀了我们的。
Those things are gonna kill us all if we don't work together.
你以为我会信你的话吗?
You think I'm going to fall for that?
你的武器对付他们没用。
Your weapons are useless against them.
我们不需要你的帮助。
We don't need your help.
我们是强大的十戒，
We are the mighty Ten Rings, and any...
……我们应该合作。
We... We should work together.
放了他们。
Release them.
放了他们!
Release them!
他们在做什么?
What are they doing?
偷灵魂来喂养黑暗的居住者。
Stealing souls to feed the Dweller-in-Darkness.
如果它足够强大，就会冲破大门。
If it grows strong enough, it will break right through the gate.
这仅仅是个开始。
That was just the beginning.
太危险了。
It's too dangerous.
我必须帮助我的朋友。
I have to help my friends.
不会死。
Don't die.
所有人马上到水里去!
Everyone to the water now!
湖!我们走吧!
To the lake! Let's go!
我们走吧!
Let's go!
嘿，你哥哥呢?
Hey, where's your brother?
我希望你知道。
I was hoping you knew.
救救我。
Save me.
瞄准天空，成败在此一举!
Aim at the sky, to win or die!
深呼吸。
Deep breath.
上气，你没什么好怕的。
Shang-Chi, you have nothing to fear.
你有我们龙的心脏。
You have the heart of our dragon.
我永远是你的一部分。你爸爸也会的。
I will always be a part of you. And your dad will too.
把我们给你的一切都变成你自己的。
Take everything we've given you and make it your own.
我真为你骄傲。
I'm so proud of you.
我们家需要你。
Our family needs you.
走了。
Go.
开弓
Draw.
放箭
Fire!
你必须阻止你父亲!
You have to stop your father!
她不在后面，爸爸。
She's not back there, Dad.
别挡我的路，小子。
Get out of my way, boy.
不。
No.
冷静点，伙计
Calm down, mate.
我没死，只是一场表演。
I'm not dead, it's just a performance.
快下来跟我一起玩。
Now get down here and play along.
我必须救她。
I have to save her.
她在叫我。
She's calling to me.
我希望这是真的。
I wish that were true.
爸爸,请。
Dad, please.
你的家人需要你。
Your family needs you.
让我出去!
Let me out!
该死
Shit.
它朝村子开去了!
It's headed for the village!
如果它得到了龙的灵魂，它将势不可挡!
If it gets our dragon's soul, it will be unstoppable!
瞄准喉咙!
Aim for the throat!
你得让我走。
You have to let me go.
放开!
Let go!
我不会再离开你了。
I'm not leaving you again.
天呐
Holy shit.
走了。
Go.
今晚，我们向那些为我们的未来而牺牲的人们致敬。
Tonight, we honour those who gave their lives so we might see another day.
他们不仅仅是战士。
They were more than warriors.
他们是我们的父母，我们的兄弟姐妹。
They were our mothers and fathers, our sisters and brothers.
虽然我们将永远铭记他们的记忆，但今晚我们让他们与我们的祖先一起安息。
And though we will always hold on to their memories, tonight we release them to rest with our ancestors.
再见,爸爸。
Farewell, Dad.
妈妈，我们会没事的。
Mum, we'll be okay.
一千年前，一千年后，我们会永远在一起。
A thousand years ago, and a thousand years from now, we will always be together.
我真的以为我们会死。
I seriously thought we were going to die.
我一天前才学会射箭，现在我在战场上，和肖恩的阿姨一起，杀了所有吸魂者，她是个了不起的，神奇的功夫女神。
And I'd only learned how to shoot a bow, like, a day earlier, now I'm on a battlefield, killing all these Soul Suckers with Shaun's aunty, who's this awesome, magical kung fu goddess.
此时此刻，我和我的妹妹正紧紧抓住《伟大的守护者》，努力不被超级灵魂吸盘吃掉。
And I'm hanging on to The Great Protector with my sister at this point, trying not to get eaten by the Mega Soul Sucker.
超级灵魂吸盘真是个讨厌的贱人。
Oh, the Mega Soul Sucker was such a nasty bitch.
是的。它想要吃掉我们龙的灵魂。
Yeah. It was trying to eat our dragon's soul.
这样它就能毁灭整个宇宙。
Which would have allowed it to destroy the entire universe.
是的。
Yeah.
我只剩下一支箭了，而我脑海里只听到我妈妈的声音在说，“快射，你这个小混蛋!”
I only had one arrow left, and all I could hear in the back of my mind was my mom's voice saying, "Just take the shot, you little mooch!"
于是，我瞄准了那个笨蛋的喉咙，让她飞了起来。-她说得很对。
And so, I aimed right for the Sucker's throat - and I let her fly. - She hit it dead on.
然后肖恩用十戒做了一个疯狂的卡米哈米哈火球把它炸了... ...他拯救了世界。
And then Shaun used the Ten Rings to do this crazy Kamehameha fireball that exploded the thing... ...and he saved the world.
是啊，那天我们失去了一些好人…
Yeah, we, uh, lost some good people that day...
但是我们成功了。
but we made it.
我们成功了。
We made it.
你嘲笑完我了吗
Are you done mocking me?
哦,不。我们不是在嘲笑你。
Oh, no. We're not mocking you.
你妹妹在哪里?
So where is this sister of yours?
她回我爸的地盘了，阻止他的行动。
She's back at my dad's compound, shutting down his operations.
是啊，他爸爸是十枚戒指的头儿一千年来都是。
Yeah, his dad was the head of The Ten Rings for the past thousand years.
两周前，你还在为小费停车，现在你却想让我相信你在从吸灵魂的怪物手中拯救世界?
Two weeks ago, you were parking cars for tips, and you want me to believe you're now saving the world from soul-sucking monsters?
我知道，你想挽回我上次说的话，但作为朋友，我不会为说了实话而道歉。
I know, you're trying to get me back for what I said last time, but I'm not gonna apologise... ...for speaking the truth as a friend.
我说的都是真心的，事实上，我觉得你现在所做的一切进一步证明了我的观点。
I really meant what I said, and, in fact, I actually think this whole bit you're doing just further proves my point.
你们显然…——什么?——商迟。
You guys are obviously... - What? - Shang-Chi.
商迟。
Shang-Chi.
嗯…在这里。
Uh... Here.
礼物。
Present.
我姓王。
My name is Wong.
我知道，先生，我是你的超级粉丝…你有戒指吗?
Yeah, I know, sir. I'm a huge fan... Do you have the rings?
嗯…是的,是的。
Uh... Yeah, yes.
好。走吧，我们有很多话要谈。
Good. Let's go, we have a lot to talk about.
你也一样。
You too.
我也是吗?
Me too?
-我觉得我们应该…-是的。
- I think we should... - Yeah.
-我们得走了-是的。
- Uh, we gotta go. - Yeah.
我知道这很疯狂，但我会给你发短信，我们再来一次。很高兴见到你，约翰。
I know this is, like, crazy, but I'm gonna text you, and we'll do this again. Nice to see you, John.
我会用Venmo给你…
I'll Venmo you for the...
你穿着你的上衣在七月四日那天，我在街上搬家我们在灯光下被逮住了从我的窗户出去，我在拍照看着天空中的烟花
You was crusin' with your top down Fourth of July I was movin' down the block We got caught at the light Out my window I was shooting my shot Watching fireworks in the sky
我在呼唤它，我在呼唤它，我在呼唤它，我在呼唤它，我在呼唤它，我在呼唤它，我在呼唤它，我在呼唤它，我在呼唤它，我在呼唤它，我在呼唤它，我在呼唤它，我在呼唤它，我在呼唤它
I'm calling it now I'm calling it now I'm calling it now You'll find love with me somehow Yes, somehow I'm calling it now In the summers we let the top down Soak up the light
我想要的只是锁定我生命中的爱就像午夜开车看天空中的烟花我现在就这么做我现在就这么做
All I wanted was just to lock down the love of my life Nice and simple like a midnight drive Watching fireworks in the sky I'm calling it now I'm calling it now I'm calling it now
你会在我身边找到真爱是的，我现在就这么说哦，哦，哦每句话，每一个字每一个名词和动词都能定义你
You'll find love with me somehow Yes, somehow I'm calling it now Ooh, ooh, ooh Every line, every word every noun and verb can define you
哦，哦，哦你很害羞，但你告诉我靠边停车现在我就在你后面我们走得有点快，但感觉是对的我们应该巡航到内华达州今晚结婚
Ooh, ooh, ooh You were shy but you told me to pull over And now I'm right behind you We was movin' kinda fast but the feeling was right We should cruise up to Nevada Get married tonight
生活很简单，只要你在我的生命中看烟花在天空中我正在呼唤它，我正在呼唤它，我正在呼唤它，你会找到爱与我，无论如何，是的，我正在呼唤它
Life is simple as long as you're in my life Watching fireworks in the sky I'm calling it now I'm calling it now I'm calling it now You'll find love with me somehow Yes, somehow I'm calling it now
嗯。
Hmm.
跟我们法典里的任何文物都不匹配。
They don't match any artefacts from our codex.
你觉得呢?
What do you think?
嗯，我不确定。
Mm, I'm not sure.
他们不是vibranium。Chitauri吗?
They're not vibranium. Chitauri?
不像我见过的任何外星科技。
Not like any alien tech I've seen.
你爸爸把它们给你之前有多久了?
How long did your dad have them before he gave them to you?
嗯…大约一千年。
Um... About a thousand years.
它们的热释光表明它们的年龄比那还要大。
Their thermoluminescence indicates they're older than that.
由很多。
By a lot.
你第一次用戒指时，我们在卡马尔泰姬陵感觉到了。
The first time you used the rings, we felt it in Kamar-Taj.
它是什么?
What is it?
一个灯塔。
A beacon.
他们在传递一个信息。
They're sending a message.
给哪里发信息?
A message to where?
我很抱歉。我得处理这件事。
I'm so sorry. I have to deal with this.
你可以向布鲁斯要我的电话号码。
You can get my number from Bruce.
很高兴见到你。
It was so nice to meet you.
是的,……我没有她的电话号码。
Yeah, I... I don't have her number.
……她经常这样做。
She... She does this a lot.
伙计们,保持安全。
Guys, stay safe.
欢迎来到马戏团。
Welcome to the circus.
我知道这让你难以接受，但你得开始习惯这一点。
I know this is a lot to take in, but you're gonna have to start getting used to that.
从现在开始，你们的人生轨迹将会是前所未有的。
From now on, the trajectory of your lives will be like nothing you've ever experienced before.
没有回头路了。
And there's no going back.
你们都有很长的路要走。
You both have a long journey ahead of you.
回家，休息一下。
Go home, get some rest.
是的。好主意。
Yeah. That's a good idea.
是的。是啊，也许我们应该这么做。
Yeah. Yeah, we probably should do that.
还是……
Or...
欢迎来到加州旅馆-多么可爱的地方-多么可爱的地方-多么可爱的面孔-多么可爱的面孔-加州旅馆有很多房间
Welcome to the Hotel California - Such a lovely place - Such a lovely place - Such a lovely face - Such a lovely face Plenty of room at the Hotel California
在一年中的任何时候在一年中的任何时候你都可以在这里找到它
- Any time of year - Any time of year You can find it here
她的思想被蒂芙尼扭曲了她开着奔驰车她有很多漂亮的男孩，她称之为朋友他们在院子里跳舞，夏日的甜蜜汗水
Her mind is Tiffany-twisted She got the Mercedes bends, uh She got a lot of pretty, pretty boys she calls friends How they dance in the courtyard, sweet summer sweat
有人为回忆而舞，有人为忘却而舞  所以我叫船长“请把我的酒拿来”
Some dance to remember, some dance to forget So I called up the Captain "Please bring me my wine"
他说"我们这里从1969年起就没有这种酒了"
He said, "We haven't had that spirit here since 1969"
那些声音仍然从遥远的地方打来，在半夜把你吵醒，只是为了听到他们说，欢迎来到加州酒店-多么可爱的地方-多么可爱的地方
And still those voices are calling from far away Wake you up in the middle of the night Just to hear them say Welcome to the Hotel California - Such a lovely place - Such a lovely place
多么可爱的脸他们在加州旅馆尽情狂欢-多么美妙的惊喜-多么美妙的惊喜带来你的不在场证明
Such a lovely face They livin' it up at the Hotel California - What a nice surprise - What a nice surprise Bring your alibis
他们在等
They're waiting.
让我们开始吧。
Let's get started.
我们有很多工作要做。
We have a lot of work to do.